JULIO CASTRO

Senior Software Engineer

julio.castro.dev@gmail.com | +41 76 513 18 64 | Zurich, Switzerland

SUMMARY

Extensive experience in software engineering from startup to large corporate levels. Proven success leading teams in various technologies including Angular, React, Nodejs or Spring Boot, resulting in highly performing, harmonious and cohesive teams with deep technical and business knowledge. Succeeded in applying mathematical and scientific skills to drive and clarify intricate and complex business challenges, resulting in bigger, better and faster achievements.

SKILLS, LANGUAGES AND INTERESTS

- Languages: Typescript, Java, Python, HTML/CSS, Javascript, SQL
- <u>Technologies:</u> Angular, React, Spring Boot, Nodejs, Nextjs, Cypress
- Other: Domain Driven Design, Clean Arquitecture, Modern Reactivity

EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance Developer at Santander Innovation Lab | Fabrik

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Santander Innovation Lab is a group of talented teams focused on creating disruptive products.
- Each application undergoes extensive and rigorous quality testing, which were costly and.
- Implemented, executed and automated a wide variety of tests. The automation was focused
- Achieved a reduction from weeks of manual work to a few minutes of execution. In addition.
- Skills: Java · Selenium · Appium · GitLab · Scrum · JIRA

Quality Assurance Developer at Santander Innovation Lab | Fabrik

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Santander Innovation Lab is a group of talented teams focused on creating disruptive products.
- Each application undergoes extensive and rigorous quality testing, which were costly and.
- Implemented, executed and automated a wide variety of tests. The automation was focused
- Achieved a reduction from weeks of manual work to a few minutes of execution. In addition.
- Skills: Java · Selenium · Appium · GitLab · Scrum · JIRA

Quality Assurance Developer at Santander Innovation Lab | Fabrik

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Santander Innovation Lab is a group of talented teams focused on creating disruptive products.
- Each application undergoes extensive and rigorous quality testing, which were costly and.
- Implemented, executed and automated a wide variety of tests. The automation was focused

- Achieved a reduction from weeks of manual work to a few minutes of execution. In addition.
- Skills: Java · Selenium · Appium · GitLab · Scrum · JIRA

Quality Assurance Developer at Santander Innovation Lab | Fabrik

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Santander Innovation Lab is a group of talented teams focused on creating disruptive products.
- Each application undergoes extensive and rigorous quality testing, which were costly and.
- Implemented, executed and automated a wide variety of tests. The automation was focused
- Achieved a reduction from weeks of manual work to a few minutes of execution. In addition.
- Skills: Java · Selenium · Appium · GitLab · Scrum · JIRA

Quality Assurance Developer at Santander Innovation Lab | Fabrik

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Santander Innovation Lab is a group of talented teams focused on creating disruptive products.
- Each application undergoes extensive and rigorous quality testing, which were costly and.
- Implemented, executed and automated a wide variety of tests. The automation was focused
- Achieved a reduction from weeks of manual work to a few minutes of execution. In addition.
- Skills: Java · Selenium · Appium · GitLab · Scrum · JIRA

Quality Assurance Developer at Santander Innovation Lab | Fabrik

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

- Santander Innovation Lab is a group of talented teams focused on creating disruptive products.
- Each application undergoes extensive and rigorous quality testing, which were costly and.
- Implemented, executed and automated a wide variety of tests. The automation was focused
- Achieved a reduction from weeks of manual work to a few minutes of execution. In addition.
- Skills: Java · Selenium · Appium · GitLab · Scrum · JIRA

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics and Computer Science from the Polytechnic University of Madrid

2017 - 2021

- Achieved an average score of 9/10.
- Awarded for multiple years with academic excellence on behalf of the city of Madrid.

LANGUAGES

- English C1
- German A2
- Spanish Native